<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home</title>
    <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jdeepd.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An interesting problem(and solution) in Probability</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/2.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/2.d/</guid>
      <description>Urn A contains 6 red and 4 black balls. Urn B contains 4 red and 6 black balls. One ball is drawn at random from Urn A and placed in Urn B. Then, one ball is drawn at random from Urn B and placed in Urn A. Now, If one ball is drawn from Urn A, find the probability that it is red. (Cengage JEE Adv Algebra, 3e)
 The question is straight forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>notes</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/notes/</guid>
      <description>Ranger tips:     Type S while in a particular directory in ranger to cd into that directory zh for toggling hidden files cw to rename file under cursor dD&amp;lt;Enter&amp;gt; to delete file under cursor For more, visit here  Donot step on your own foot techniques:     Install packages wisely. All package binaries installed by pacman go into /usr/bin. All packages installed by other means should(must?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bisect: A severely underated Git command</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/1.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 21:19:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/1.d/</guid>
      <description>git bisect    Ever faced a situation where you made multiple commits to your project only to break a feature which you are sure it worked properly before you went on the commit spree?
How on earth do you even plan to begin debugging the code in such a scenario?
One could go on a brute force approach but wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be much easier(to debug) if git just tells you which commit messed up your feature?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>about me    I am a student who gets bored easily. So, if I get free time, I write some blogs.
Email : (Can be found on my github profile)
about site     powered by hugo theme: hugo-coder font: iosevka social: twt; discord  about setup     laptop: vivobook x512-fl os: arch linux on gnome editor: neovim term: kitty with tmux  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
