<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home</title>
    <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 21:01:32 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jdeepd.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[GSoC] Week 1: Diving into ref-filters and for-each-ref</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/7.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 21:01:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/7.d/</guid>
      <description>So this week, I dived into the codebase of ref-filters.c and for builtins/for-each-ref.c. In this blog, I will try to give a brief overview of those.
Before that, you should know what Git References or simply, refs are.
git for-each-ref is a simple command for listing out all(or maybe some) of the refs in a repository in a specific format. For ex, you want to print out the refs inside .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[GSoC] Week 0: Community Bonding Period</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/6.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/6.d/</guid>
      <description>So, My proposal to the org git got accepted for GSoC 2022. For the next few days, I will be exploring the codebase, also try to make some side contributions under the mentorship of Christian and Hariom. I am already in contact with them regarding the proposal.
Till now, I have read most the &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; docs in Hacking Git. Yesterday, I was reading this very interesting tutorial on Write yourself a Git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bit masking and bit flags. Managing data efficiently</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/5.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/5.d/</guid>
      <description>Suppose you are given a situation where you have to produce some output which depends on various arguments(flags) that the user provides.
For ex, lets say you are given a number and you are asked to do some tests on it:
 Is the number postive? Is the magnitude(number) odd? Is the magnitude(number) prime?  You are also asked to save all the test results in memory so that you can pass it to other functions if required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A tour of my workflow</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/3.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/3.d/</guid>
      <description>My main workflow consists of multiple browser tabs, kitty and a tmux session along with neovim. All of them are customised to my liking ofcourse(although kitty is just pretty in default)
For browser, I primarily use Chrome(don&amp;rsquo;t ask me why. Its just that all my accounts get instant login there.) I use the vimium extension and Adblock extension Both of them work out of the box with no configuration required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An interesting problem(and solution) in Probability</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/2.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/2.d/</guid>
      <description>Urn A contains 6 red and 4 black balls. Urn B contains 4 red and 6 black balls. One ball is drawn at random from Urn A and placed in Urn B. Then, one ball is drawn at random from Urn B and placed in Urn A. Now, If one ball is drawn from Urn A, find the probability that it is red. (Cengage JEE Adv Algebra, 3e)
 The question is straight forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>notes</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/notes/</guid>
      <description>Ranger tips:     Type S while in a particular directory in ranger to cd into that directory zh for toggling hidden files cw to rename file under cursor dD&amp;lt;Enter&amp;gt; to delete file under cursor For more, visit here  Donot step on your own foot techniques:     Install packages wisely. All package binaries installed by pacman go into /usr/bin. All packages installed by other means should(must?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>s1: Some notes about char **argv</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/subnote1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/subnote1/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: Notes can have errors. Mail me if you find some.     Few points to remember:
 Array indexing in C A trivial note about %s placeholder You cant actually pass an array to a function in C   Consider this code:
int main(int argc, char** argv) {  return 0; } &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; ./test in1 in2 Here,
 argc gives the number of arguments passed(3 in this case) argv gives you access to all the command line arguments passed when running the program  argv[0] is the first argument passed(i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bisect: A severely underated Git command</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/1.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 21:19:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/1.d/</guid>
      <description>git bisect    Ever faced a situation where you made multiple commits to your project only to break a feature which you are sure it worked properly before you went on the commit spree?
How on earth do you even plan to begin debugging the code in such a scenario?
One could go on a brute force approach but wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be much easier(to debug) if git just tells you which commit messed up your feature?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>about me    I am a student who gets bored easily. So, if I get free time, I write some blogs.
My interests(not equivalent to expertise):
 Machine Learning/AI/some parts of Mathematics Hardware and low level programming Backend Development Linux and Networking Badminton/Video Editing/Memes/Anime Finances and Stock Market  Email : (Can be found on my github profile)
about site     powered by hugo theme: hugo-coder font: iosevka social: twt; discord  The source of this site is licensed under MIT License</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
