<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GSoC on home</title>
    <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/tags/gsoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GSoC on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 15:04:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jdeepd.github.io/tags/gsoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[GSoC] Week 5: Signature atom</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/11.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 15:04:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/11.d/</guid>
      <description>In the process to make pretty-formats use ref-filter&amp;rsquo;s logic, it is important to ensure that ref-filter has an &amp;ldquo;equivalent format&amp;rdquo; for all the pretty formats. There are these &amp;quot;%G*&amp;quot; pretty formats which are for getting information related to GPG signatures of commits. ref-filter however, do not have these format options. So, migrating completely, we have to first implement this format in ref-filter. Lucky for me, Hariom already did it in 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[GSoC] Week 4: Time to get some reviews</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/10.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/10.d/</guid>
      <description>The branch that I am working on is derived from Hariom&amp;rsquo;s work in 2020-21. It has over 30 commits and many of the commits are yet to be reviewed by the mailing list. So we (me and my mentors) decided it&amp;rsquo;s time we slowly put some commits in the mailing list for reviews. Any requested change can be done easily right now than later.
Apart from that, there is one more bug that I am trying to figure out how to solve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[GSoC] Week 3: The coding[debugging] phase</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/9.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/9.d/</guid>
      <description>All hail GDB
This week started off with a bug. git branch was not working with the verbose flag. It was causing a realloc error. For around 10 minutes, I tried to read some code in cmd_branch, try to figure out where the verbose option leads to, until I gave up, totally finding myself in the middle of a codemaze.
This is where GDB comes to the rescue. I knew using basic GDB but never used it on a big enough codebase like Git so I was reluctant to use it in the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[GSoC] Week 2: Getting it all together</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/8.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/8.d/</guid>
      <description>This week was a bit engaging(probably the most engaging till now). So, I had to start off where Hariom left. His work already ported most of the pretty formats to use ref-filter&amp;rsquo;s logic. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just start off from that branch directly since its more than a year old. A lot of changes have happened since then.
So first, I had to rebase pretty-lib-2.0.3 onto current master. I pulled that branch and began rebasing to master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[GSoC] Week 1: Diving into ref-filters and for-each-ref</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/7.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 21:01:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/7.d/</guid>
      <description>So this week, I dived into the codebase of ref-filters.c and for builtins/for-each-ref.c. In this blog, I will try to give a brief overview of those.
Before that, you should know what Git References or simply, refs are.
git for-each-ref is a simple command for listing out all(or maybe some) of the refs in a repository in a specific format. For ex, you want to print out the refs inside .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[GSoC] Week 0: Community Bonding Period</title>
      <link>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/6.d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdeepd.github.io/posts/6.d/</guid>
      <description>So, My proposal to the org git got accepted for GSoC 2022. For the next few days, I will be exploring the codebase, also try to make some side contributions under the mentorship of Christian and Hariom. I am already in contact with them regarding the proposal.
Till now, I have read most the &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; docs in Hacking Git. Yesterday, I was reading this very interesting tutorial on Write yourself a Git.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
